Phone: +254791525289
Email: mainakaranja2001@gmail.com
GitHub: https://www.github.com/jaykaranja

A dedicated software engineer who builds with passion and with a goal to meet expected standards. Skilled in building fully-fledged systems with minimum complexity using languages such as C# and Python for backend development, JavaScript for UI/UX using frameworks such as React and NodeJS and more stacks. Also highly familiar with cloud engineering and Devops using platforms such as Microsoft Azure. Very determined to learn new skills everyday as demonstrated by my work and software engineering experience.

## **RELEVANT SKILLS**

Experience in using technology stacks such as C#, .NET, Python (Frameworks such as Django), JavaScript (ReactJS, NodeJS), Basic HTML and JavaScript, CICD flows and cloud platforms such as Microsoft Azure.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

BusinessCloud Limited (January 2023-Present) - Senior Software Engineer

- Successfully led a team of engineers in building fully-working beautiful UIs for the company's projects using ReactJS.
- Provided input in solving problems that we had to resolve using code and using the best software development practices while utilizing good OOP practices to ensure good time and space complexity.
- Managed to engineer complex components which would be used in some of the projects we were working on.
- Was part of a cloud engineering team where we built microservices and deployed them successfully in Microsoft Azure.

Woodridge Senior School (August 2022-December 2022) - Software Engineer

Managed to develop a fully working system for the school so as to help it gain more public acknowledgement and run some of the tasks the staff had to do manually and integrated them into a computer system to ease their tasks and make managerial work flawless.

Personal projects (May 2019-August 2022) - Software Engineer

• Since I finished a software engineering course, I managed to develop a couple of projects for learning purposes and skillset improvement from working with APIs, music apps, sales management systems and more.

## **EDUCATION EXPERIENCE**

Zalego Academy (January 2019-May 2019) - Software Engineering

- Learnt basic web development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Learnt web development using Python (Django specifically)
- Learnt mobile app development for Android using Java.

Kiriti Secondary School (January 2015-November 2018) - High School

• Completed my Kenya Certificate of Secondary School education and managed to score a grade of B-.